Why did Jesus choose a betrayer?
Some say it was to fulfill the scriptures true,
but he chose to write down those scriptures in the first place.
So even in the Old Testament he was choosing Judas.
One of the reasons, and I'm gonna give you a few, yeah,
but one of the reasons Jesus chose a betrayer
as one of his apostles,
knowing it was the person we betray him,
is because Jesus is the son of David.
And he's not just the son of David
in the sense that he's a descendant of David.
He's the son of David, and that he's very like David
in many ways.
We talk this morning of Jesus being liked,
Joseph, he's also like Jacob.
But when it comes to David,
Jesus had many areas in which you could say,
well, this is like David.
This is like King David.
David was born in Bethlehem.
Jesus was born in Bethlehem.
David ruled W was born in Bethlehem.
He ruled in Jerusalem.
Jesus will one day rule in Jerusalem.
David had a shepherd, and he fed the flock,
and he was willing to die for that flock.
Jesus is a shepherd who fed the flock,
and is willing to die for his flock.
But very importantly, with all these similar things,
born in the same place, will rule in the same place,
so ship it over the flock.
One way in which Jesus was fundamentally the same as David,
or experience, or all similar to David,
is that David had very dear friends who betrayed him.